在上一集里
Previously on Transformers Prime...
救护车 大黄蜂的发声器是怎么回事？
Ratchet, what happened to Bumblebee's voice box?
我们勇敢的侦察兵被霸天虎抓住并遭严刑逼供
Our brave scout was captured by Megatron's forces and interrogated.
大黄蜂几乎成为了一堆废铁
Bumblebee was left for scrap
一位战地医生稳住了他的伤势
well, a field medic managed to stabilize his condition.
不过那个医生…本可以做得更好
Though, the medic could've done better.
火种源在上！
By the Allspark!
大黄蜂的变形齿轮不是损坏
Bumblebee's T-cog isn't damaged.
而是不见了
It's missing!
那是一种变形关节吗？
Is that like a T-bone?
是我们用来扫描车辆和变形的器官
It's the organ that allows us to scan vehicles and transform.
你来这儿做什么？
Why ARE you here?
来与你们结盟
To propose an alliance.
变形齿轮不是技术产品 而是生理器官
A T-cog isn't technology. It is biology.
奥利安走之前留下的坐标还有两个
We possess two more sets of coordinates which Orion decrypted before departing our ranks.
看看我们还能找到哪些失落已久的宝藏
Let us see what other long lost treasures we might be re-united with.
这简直是糟糕透顶的主意…
Of all the scrap-brained ideas!
在大黄蜂失去车辆形态的时候\N带他去执行一个可能需要追击的任务？
Taking Bumblbee into a potential chase scenario when he no longer has the ability to access his wheels!?
是他硬要去的
He improvised.
嘿 小蜂醒了
Hey! Bee is waking up.
你已经失去了发声器和变形齿轮
You've already lost your voice-box and your T-cog.
现在连火种也不想要了吗？
Were you really trying to add your Spark to the list?
别气馁 大黄蜂
Don't say that Bumblebee.
你并非一无是处
You are not useless!
听着 尽管我不想打断你们的伤感对白
Look. I hate to break up the pity-party
但虎子们刚刚把铁堡的第二件遗物收入了囊中
but the ‘Cons just added unknown Iacon Payday number 2 to their armory.
责备或表扬都解决不了问题
Neither blame nor praise will modify past events.
但我们不能再承受不必要的风险了
But we cannot afford to take further unnecessary risks.
大黄蜂 从现在起你不许离开基地
Bumblebee, you are not to leave our base.
直到我们找回你的器官
Not until we can retrieve your missing biomechanism.
大黄蜂感到沮丧是正常反应
Bumblebee is right to be less than hopeful.
但你我都知道有种办法能让他恢复健全
But you and I both know that exists a way to make him whole again.
器官移植 但那需要一个捐献者
A transplant. But that would require a donor.
你面前就站着一位捐献者
You need to look no further than the Autobot standing before you.
你很慷慨 老朋友
A generous offer, old friend.
但这不过是换一个人去坐轮椅罢了
But your solution would merely trade one Autobot's handicap for another's.
我不需要依赖变形齿轮…
I don't rely upon my T-cog!
不像大黄蜂那么需要
Not like Bumblebee does.
变形能力在我身上是一种浪费
The ability to transform is virtually wasted on me.
我整天都呆在这里
This is where I spend my days
我的思维和技艺才是我的价值体现
where my thoughts and hands are of value.
而并非武器和车轮
Not my weapons or wheels.
我们的队伍不能再少一个能上战场的战士了
Our team can't afford to be shy even one warrior in the field.
你说的有道理
You make a compelling case
但你要相信我们能够找回大黄蜂的变形齿轮
But know that we will find Bumblebee's T-cog.
擎天柱 机械党都是野蛮人
Optimus. M.E.C.H. - are savages.
谁知道他们已经对变形齿轮做了什么？
Who knows what damage they may have already inflicted upon it? Or...
谁知道我还能不能修好它？
Or if I would be able to repair it?
救护车 你已经尽力了
Ratchet. You did everything in your power.
拜托
Puh-lease.
你觉得这只是因为我没能修好大黄蜂的发声器吗？
Do you really think this is simply about my inability to restore Bumblebee's voicebox?
我…我只是为了我们的侦察兵好…
I... I just want to do what is right. For our scout.
为了我们的队伍
For the team.
干得好 击倒
Excellent work, Knockout.
为您效犬马之劳 威震天陛下
I live to serve, Lord Megatron.
不过这到底是个什么玩意？
But what exactly is it?
啊！
Ah!
现在知道了吧？
Now you know.
我好像漏了点传动液…
I think I leaked a little transmission fluid.
锁定位置
Source located.
没错 很丰盛 不是吗 赛拉斯？
Yess. Gratifying, isn't it, Silas?
我常常建议威震天寻找人类盟友
I often advised Megatron to seek out human allies.
毕竟 似乎人类偶尔也能助汽车人一臂之力
After all, it seems to provide the Autobots with an occasional edge.
但作为一个声名在外的卓越战略家
But despite his reputation as a brilliant strategist
威震天竟然心胸狭窄到
Megatron is woefully small-minded
不愿跟比我们心胸更小的人类合作
when it comes to working with minds smaller than our own.
我是指在尺寸上
He was simply referring to... head size.
你这辈子闭过嘴吗？
Do you ever not speak?
我有说过我曾亲手解决掉一个汽车人吗？
Did I mention that I've personally extinguished an Autobot?
能量体 最纯净原始的姿态…
Energon... In its purest state.
正待开采
Ready to be mined.
还需要提炼 我的血肉同胞
And processed. My flesh-covered compatriot.
助我们成就霸业吧
To give us the edge.
很快我也会躺在病床上 不言而喻
Obviously, since I am the other patient involved
我将无法执行手术操作
... I will be unable to perform the surgery.
因此 你们中的一人必须来代替我
Therefore, one of you must serve as my proxy.
不行 你更擅长破坏
Nah-uh. Better at breaking things.
呼
Phew.
阿尔茜
Arcee.
擎天柱的手要更为稳健
Optimus has steadier hands.
稳是稳 但是太大了 伸不进我的身体
Steady, and much too large to be rooting around beneath my hood.
阿尔茜 你能行的
Arcee, you can do this.
你跟他们一样结实
You're steely as they come.
上战场可以 手术台却不行
On a battlefield, not in an operating theater.
都一样 你是主刀的 不是挨刀的
Same thing. As long as you're behind the knife. Not under it.
大黄蜂该不会从此变成一辆笨重的救护车了吧？
Does this mean Bumblebee's gonna transform into an ambulance from now on or be all cranky?
我只是觉得那样怪怪的
'cause that would be weird.
引导休眠
Inducing stasis.
啊 啊 啊 你可以等…
Yeah-yeah...
结束了再…
you can thank me... when...
谢我
it's over.
好了 大黄蜂
Okay, Bumblebee.
该你了
Your turn.
怎么了？
What's happening?
救护车没心跳了！
Ratchet's flatlining!
不是他
No he isn't!
是铁堡的定位信号
It's an Iacon homing beacon.
我们再次收到这个信号
If we’re picking up a signal
说明虎子们又挖出了一件遗物
it means the 'Cons just unearthed another relic.
汽车人 准备出发
Autobots, prepare to roll out!
好极了！
...Yess!
病人除外
Except for our patients.
最好中止休眠
It would be best to interrupt stasis.
擎天柱 重大新闻！
Prime! Breaking news.
嗯 擎天柱呢？
Huh? Where's Prime?
听着 告诉他…
Look. Let him know
我从卫星收到了图像信息
I've just received access to satellite imagery
我认为那是机械党的老巢
which I believe pinpoints the center of operations of MECH.
哦 慈爱的主啊…
Oh for the love of..!
找个能说话的来！
Give me someone who speaks something other than "bleep"!
我可以帮忙
I can help...
咋了 有哪个双生兽的发声器需要修理吗？
What?! Do I hear a Fuzor in need of voice-box repair?!
双生兽是什么？
What's a fuzor?!
那边怎么回事？
What's going on over there?
我能搞定
I am able!
不信去问嘲弄兽
Just ask Bantor.
他原来是只狒狒 后来我在他身体里塞进一只老虎
He was all mandrill before I put a tiger in his tank!
不行 小蜂 擎天柱说过不让你离开基地
But Bee! You heard what Optimus said about leaving the base.
把坐标发过来 福勒探员
Send the coordinates, Agent Fowler.
我们… 一定转交给擎天柱
We'll... make sure Optimus gets them.
我搞不懂
I don't get it.
磨坏了我的锤子
All this chipping away with my hammer
就只为了给威震天一把新锤子？
just to bring Megatron another hammer?
这锤子是13位元祖领袖的圣物
That "hammer" is a sacred relic of the thirteen original Primes.
真的?
Really??
那东西不是霸天虎的毁灭性武器？
Isn't that the opposite of Decepticon Doomsday Device?
这不难理解 除了缴获的霸天虎武器
It would stand to reason that in addition to confiscated Decepticon artillery
铁堡地下室中意义重大的宝物也被转移了出去
any artifacts of great significance stored in the vaults of Iacon would also have been shipped offworld.
而这是其中最为宝贵的…
And none would be greater than this.
卓天越之锤
The Forge of Solus Prime.
它具有把原料变成道具的神奇力量
For it possesses the power to mystically infuse raw material with working mechanisms.
就是说 要是我们有了它
As in... If we had it we can pound any weapon we can dream of into existence?
不如说我们有望为大黄蜂重新造一个变形齿轮
Or... possibly construct a new T-cog for Bumblebee.
进行融合
Initiate transfusion.
起作用了
It's working.
能量体 它能为我们未来的军队创造奇迹
Energon! It will do wonders for our future army.
你未来的军队
... your future army.
事实上 我们很快就能一睹这神奇的变形了
In fact, we are mere moments from beholding the miracle of transformation.
失去了变形齿轮 他没有武装
No T-cog! He's unarmed.
可以出土了
Time to get a grip.
汽车人 试试我的新涂层保护装备
Autobots! Check out my new finish-protector.
触手可及 又遥不可及
So close, and yet!
我们的位置和原型机暴露了
The location and prototype have been compromised!
消灭入侵者 拿回变形齿轮
Destroy the intruder and meet me at the rendezvous point!
然后与我会合
With my T-cog!
我不是你的小卒子！
I am not one of your foot-soldiers!
我是顾问！
I am a consultant!
再靠近一步 就把你的小器官变成废铁
One step, and your precious biomech is scrap.
救护车 你感觉怎么样？
Ratchet! How are you feeling?
很好 实际上 我感觉完全没有变化
Fine. In fact, I feel as though nothing has changed.
擎天柱！
Prime!
怎么了 福勒探员？
What is it, Agent Fowler?
擎天柱去那个坐标了吗？
Has Prime received the coordinates?
坐标？
Coordinates?
疑似机械党的据点！
Possible MECH location!
半小时前我就把坐标发过去了！
I've sent them half an hour ago!
呃 别担心 福勒探员
Um, don't worry, Agent Fowler
这件事正在处理
it's taken care of.
擎天柱还在和虎子们缠斗
Optimus had to go lock fenders with some 'Cons.
所以 大黄蜂替他去了
So... Bumblebee went instead.
什么？
What?!
大黄蜂不能去！
Bumblebee can't do that!
他还在手术恢复期！
He's recovering from surgery!
关于那个嘛…
About that...
怎么着？你要开枪吗？
Or you'll what? Shoot?
多么悲惨 无法变成车辆形态
How sad to be incapable of achieving vehicle mode
无法体会高速的快感
experiencing the sensation of speed!
作为一个失败的汽车人
How very pathetic...
真是可怜
to be a failure as an Autobot.
啊!
Ahhh!
我要飞啦 因为我能！
Time to jet! Because I can!
我的变形齿轮
My T-cog.
哦 那个
Yes... that.
很可惜 在惨烈的战斗中它被摧毁了
Unfortunately, it was destroyed during the ferocity of battle.
嗯 只是一个暂时的小插曲
A temporary setback.
还有其他汽车人 其他的变形齿轮
Other Autobots, other T-cogs.
我们很快就能找到另一个
we shall find a replacement soon enough.
那不够快
Not "soon enough".
现在就要！
Now!
啊啊啊!
Aghhhh!
因为他发明了将护盾发生器用于输出的战术
For the most creative use of a shield generator in a supporting role
所以获胜的将是击倒！
the winner is... Knockout!
我的更大
Mine's bigger!
隔板！
Bulkhead!
三思！
Nah-uh.
在地球上找到了领袖的圣物？
A relic of Primes here on Earth?
奥利安・派克斯再一次
The Decepticon Cause is once again
为霸天虎事业作出了伟大贡献
indebted to the contributions of Orion Pax.
我还好
... I'm fine.
擎天柱 我们有理由确信
Optimus!
我们找到了机械党的老巢
We have reason to believe we have located MECH's center of operations.
大黄蜂已经去了
Bumblebee is already there.
嗯 什么？
... What?
汽车人!
Autobots!!
我的变形齿轮！
... My T-cog!
救护车 重新打开环陆桥 准备手术
Ratchet. Re-open the Groundbridge. And prepare for surgery.
都怪我 威震天拿到了铸锤
Thanks to me, Megatron has the Forge.
卓天越之锤的确对我们大有用处
While we would’ve put the Forge of Solus Prime to valuable use
但我们无需担忧威震天拿到它
I do not believe we have reason to fear Megatron's possesion of it.
嗯 这看起来不象是\N巨无霸福特堡垒级的核子冲击炮
Uh, It doesn't look like a Fortress Maximus' grade nucleon shock cannon.
正如我设想的一样
It is as I suspected.
没有领袖力量去激活它
Without the power of a Prime to activate it
这个锤子只能被扔进工具箱
the Forge is merely another addition to our tool-chest.
不过有一点 我们必须尽可能避免让领袖拿到它
One we must nonetheless keep as far as possible from the reach of a Prime.
我…尽力了
I... did what I could.
我们的侦察员已经得到了最好的治疗 老朋友
Our scout could not have been in better hands, old friend.
我们不能再移植救护车的变形齿轮给大黄蜂了？
And we didn’t stick with Plan A and let Ratchet donate his cog -- why?
大黄蜂不会接受的
Bumblebee wouldn't accept it.
大黄蜂 轻一点！
Bumblebee! Easy.
慢点 你需要时间恢复
Please! Recovery takes time.
创伤十分严重
The damage was... severe.
去哪儿都行
Hah, anywhere!
尽管开吧
Just drive!
小心点
Go easy!
注意遵守试驾流程！
Adhere to standard break-in procedure!
哇喔!
Ho-ho.
当时小蜂的变形齿轮看起来都要进废品堆了
Bee's T-cog looked like ready for the scrapyard.
难以置信 医官能把它修好
Hard to believe that Doc repaired it.
救护车今天修好的可不仅仅是一个变形齿轮
That is not all that Ratchet repaired today.